ABHIRAMI SIMI ANILKUMAR

128 A, Baldwin's Lane, Croxley Green, Rickmansworth, WD33LJ (+447767986553)

ĭ abhiramisa97@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhirami-s-a-196708127/

https://abhiramisa.github.io/

PROFILE & CAREER OBJECTIVE:

A prospective data analyst who is organised and strategic in problem-solving having two years of experience in the software industry. A proactive, quality-focused, and solutions-oriented professional with extensive experience in solving business problems with various data analytics tools to identify improvement areas and deliver actionable recommendations.

CORE SKILLS:

- Python
- Statistical Analysis
- Power Bi
- Data Analytics
- SQL

- Microsoft Excel
- R Programming Language
- Marketing Analytics
- HDFS

- HR and Strategic Analytics
- HTML
- Linux
- Docker

EDUCATION:

September 2021 - September 2022: University of Exeter - MSc Business Analytics

- **Key modules**: Marketing Analytics, Operation Analytics, Database Technologies, Strategy and HR Analytics, Design Intelligence, and Data Analytics.
- Collected and analysed data from a statistical data analysis perspective using Python and R programming languages.
- Created a mini analytics project on employee evaluation for promotion using Python Visualisation techniques to identify key metrics using various libraries, including Pandas and NumPy.
- Created a flight booking database application using MySQL and performed the process of merging the database into a NoSQL server using MongoDB to store various data types efficiently.
- Analysed data and created Dashboards using Tableau for superstore analysis.
- Created a Marketing Analytics Toolkit using core analytical tools, including Market Response models, and used R to create and identify clusters of customer data for the Intel smartwatch relaunch as part of a marketing analytics project.
- Mentee under Katharine Daubney, Continuous Improvement Black Belt at OVO to meet monthly
 for sector insights and one-to-one careers advice and guidance over a six-month period as part of
 the Career Mentor Scheme.
- Mentored a group of six January intake students to support them through navigating their year at the University of Exeter as a part of the Buddy Up Scheme.
- As a management rep, I was responsible for collecting views and opinions from students, including praise and concerns regarding all aspects of the course. This feedback was used to create solutions and encourage positive change for the University of Exeter student experience.
- Created a food demand forecasting model to predict food consumption trends and revenue generation. After reviewing and using various regression tools and statistical models, the final forecasting software was made using the ETS model.

2015 – 2019: Sree Chitra Thirunal College of Engineering (Ernakulam, India) – Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication and Engineering (Distinction)

- Designed and developed an eye-tracking home automation system for people suffering from locked-in syndrome.
- Part of the core team (Finance and Sponsorship) of Cult A Way, the annual techno-cultural fest of Sree Chitra Thirunal College of Engineering.

Excel Crash Course - Spreadsheet Formulas for Finance Certification - Corporate Finance Institute **Responsive Website Basics: Code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript Certification** - University of London

WORK EXPERIENCE:

June 2019 - June 2021: Flytxt Mobile Solutions (Thiruvananthapuram, India) - Software Developer

- Product: NeonDx FlytxtEnvironment: Agile Scrum
- Platforms: Windows, Linux
- Technologies: Python, Oracle, MySQL, Docker, Hadoop, Hive
- Tools: PyCharm, Oracle SQL Developer, Git, Jira, MySQL Workbench
- Designed, coded, tested and debugged new features and enhancements to Flytxt products over the Big Data platform.
- Followed best practices of software development and got involved in build and deployment.
- Made use of new technologies and techniques in enterprise programming to keep Flytxt products at the forefront of mobile marketing and advertising technology.
- Learned new technologies and shared them with colleagues in multiple KT sessions.
- Resolved technical issues and development impediments faced by team members.
- Researched, designed, implemented and managed over 35 software programs.

11/06/2018 - 21/06/2018: Keltron (Thiruvananthapuram, India) - Intern

- Developed a robotic car using Arduino UNO.
- Worked as a team, coding and developing the software algorithm.
- Received recognition from supervisors for exemplary creativity and thinking.